{
  "reference_number": "7793",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": "Please remain strong, and ensure that exemptions are on a zero budget like basis. It must be reviewed regularly with a clear need to\n decrease concessions or exemption over time toward the goal line. An economic model needs to be adopted that will disperse the\n net goal if entities go bankrupt with a high unpaid carbon bill to remain on target. Preferably, a continuously evolving algorithm be\n\n applied by the Climate Change Commission to track the data and model performance and make or recommend changes to ETS and\n policy accordingly and is measured against critical and key measures in the outcomes or at least the reporting and response to\n change."
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Carbon Dioxide - Reducing net carbon dioxide emissions to zero by 2050",
      "answer_index": 13,
      "notes": "I am aware as a resident and a high carbon worker that I will be highly affected by such changes. I want to also target international\n travel, as so far, this is subsidised by zero taxed fuel and exemptions. I expect to pay more for overseas travel and goods and am\n happy to pay more for such luxuries."
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions (including from new forest planting) and using some emissions reductions from overseas (international carbon units) that have strong environmental safeguards",
      "answer_index": 2,
      "notes": "We need to strive to meet targets internally without excessive concessions to domestic producers and offsets from overseas as this\n could drain funding from domestic use. However, the issue is global and we need to be able to think globally to allow a buffer for a\n studied and targeted approach rather than ad-hoc firefighting on this vital issue. We must set targets early though, so that\n\n businesses, families and all of us can work toward this goal with a clear starting framework."
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "It must be a standard, to which we can excel or achieve early but not make excuses and change our stance on.There has been\n decades of thinking and debate on this. There is ample data, knowledge and wisdom on this issue to make the right choices first\n\n time by including key science and policy."
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "No - emissions budgets should not be able to be changed",
      "answer_index": 9,
      "notes": "How we achieve the objective may change, but lets be fair and clear on this, each of the budget objectives must stick."
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Except to close down exemptions and tighten the budget."
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Some of the points seem to0 fluffy and grey. Yes, I agree there is great advantage to seeking expert knowledge and skill and having\n\ndedicated team or organisation, but that any industry contributing opinions regardless of pending products or trade marks must\nprovide proof, not of concept but of deliverable viable market for their technological solution they want considered. Along with clear\nand realistic probabilities of market development where it is based on product and market dependencies. An example I can think of\n\nstraight away, where science and technology advisers and policy panels in California have been continuously misrepresented to by\nthe car and petrochemical industry about the TCO, viability of Hydrogen fuel cells, and their realistic time to mass market availability.\n\nAlso obscuring the cost competitiveness and the ability to produce and store hydrogen without expensive and carbon intensive\nprocesses. For at least sixty years hydrogen fuel cells have been in the making, and yes the experience curve could take effect, but\n\nindustries have been presenting exceedingly optimistic views of where they are on the experience curve, and the pure electric and\nsurrounding renewable infrastructure and storage solutions were on a clearer and cleaner experience curve that was apparent 12\n\nyears ago and became obvious six years ago. My impression is that serious experts may have been able to demonstrate those points\ntwice as early but were overwhelmed by vaporware promises from big business. I implore potential Climate Change Commissioners to\nkeep in mind that industry should be able to divulge their strategy, figures, assumptions and demonstrate more than just some\n\nprototypes on the technology front rather than try to engage in pie-in-the-sky futurism with industry."
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Makes decisions itself in respect of the number of units available in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 10,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Please only post my first name and notes. Please do not include my phone, email, address, or surname on your website.\n\n\n\n\n You have elected to withhold your personal details from publication."
    }
  ]
}
